Kevin Stowe, Ph.D.

kevincstowe@gmail.com

in LinkedIn

Website

Scholar

About Me

I am a research scientist and natural language processing/artificial intelligence professional. My interests include natural language generation, linguistics-informed machine learning, and responsible AI. I have 10+ years of experience in the fields of NLP, AI, and Linguistics, with expertise in software development, model training and deployment, data collection/analysis, and deep learning.

Employment History

2024 - · · · ·

Research Scientist, Educational Testing Service (ETS), Princeton, NJ

2022 - 2024

Associate Research Scientist

- Automated Content Generation (ACG) team: building machine learning methods for the generation of evaluation of testing/educational content.
- Implement and explore state-of-the-art deep learning and LLM methodology, focusing on novel techniques for training, prompting, and evaluation.
- Fairness, bias, and accessibility project leader, exploring socio-technical solutions for responsible generation of educational content.

2019 - 2022

- **Postdoctoral Researcher**, Ubiquitous Knowledge Processing (UKP), TU Darmstadt
 - Lead research in metaphor generation, dataset creation, social media analysis during crisis events, and more, yielding top-tier conference publications.
- 2013 2019
- **Research Assistant**, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO

Education

2013 - 2019

■ Ph.D., University of Colorado

Joint Degree in Linguistics and Computer Science

Thesis: Syntactic and semantic improvements to computational metaphor processing

2009 - 2011

Master of Arts, Indiana University

Computational Linguistics Track

2004 - 2009

Bachelor of Arts, Michigan State University

Linguistics

Skills

Programming

Python, Java, R, PHP, Javascript, SQL

Toolkits

HuggingFace, PyTorch/Tensorflow, OpenAI, ScikitLearn, NLTK, Spacy, Gensim

Environments

Git, AWS (S₃, EC₂, SageMaker, etc), Linux/Unix/Mac/Windows

Misc.

Scientific research, writing, and presentation; client communications, team/project leadership, interdisciplinary collaboration

Languages

Native English, fluent German, beginner Russian

Select Publications

- Stowe, K. et al. Identifying Fairness Issues in Automatically Generated Testing Content. 19th Workshop on Innovative Use of NLP for Building Educational Applications (BEA). eprint: 2404.15104 (cs.CL).

 Phttps://aclanthology.org/2024.bea-1.20 (2024).
- Stowe, K., Utama, P. & Gurevych, I. IMPLI: Investigating NLI Models' Performance on Figurative Language. *Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)*, 5375–5388.

 https://aclanthology.org/2022.acl-long.369 (May 2022).